Guide to the Brigitte Hoy Carnochan Papers relating to research on Janet Lewis, 1930-1994
Department of Special Collections
Brigitte Hoy Carnochan Papers relating to research on Janet Lewis,
1930-1994
Special Collections M0866
Carnochan, Brigitte Hoy.
4.25 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Gift of Brigitte Hoy Carnochan, 1996 and 1997.
Scope and Content
Correspondence, original works by Lewis, original works about Lewis, publications, newsclippings, photographs, audio cassettes, one 8 mm film, and 3 videos.
Container List
- Incoming correspondence to Brigitte Carnochan, 1982-1994, including a poem by Janet Lewis, "Lenore's Bear," corrected typescript, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- "Valentine Burnet," typescript by Janet Lewis, nd (Box 1, Folder 2)
- "Valentine Burnet," typescript by Janet Lewis, nd (Box 1, Folder 3)
- "Valentine Burnet," typescript by Janet Lewis, nd (Box 1, Folder 4)
- "The Legend of Neengay," opera-oratorio: typescript by Janet Lewis, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Commonwealth Club medal, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Henry Ramsey typescript, "Yvor Winters and Janet Lewis in their late 20s and early 30s," 1984 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- William H. Slavick. "Introduction" to Elizabeth Madox Roberts' The tTme of Man: a Novel, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- "Le Retour de Martin Guerre," subject file (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Photocopies of poems read by J. Lewis at Santa Fe, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Reviews of Lewis's work, including Dana Gioia's "Poetry Chronicle," inThe Hudson Review, 1981, and Michael T. Ryan's "Introduction," in Janet and DeLoss: Poems and Pictures, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Announcements (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Programs (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Illustration artwork (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Dinner invitations, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- William Slavick's copy of "The Poetry Club of the University of Chicago: Bibliography (Early, Major, Collected)" 4-page typescript, nd (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Clippings (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Clippings (Box 1, Folder 18)
- 7 photographs by Margo Davis, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Negatives [by Brigitte Carnochan?], 1983 and nd (Box 1, Folder 20)
- 2 cassette tapes of "The Wife of Martin Guerre," libretto by Janet Lewis, music by William Bergsma, nd (Box 1, Folder 21)
- 2 cassette tapes: interview of Lewis by Catherine Parke, 1989, and "Selected Poems, 1930-1982" by Peggy Pond Church, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- B. Carnochan, "An interview with Janet Lewis," in Canto, Review of the Arts, 1980., (several copies) (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Diana Hendry, "Before unjust Tribunals; the use of Circumstantial Evidence in the Work of Janet Lewis." English literature disseration, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Thomas Simmons, "Erotic Reckonings; Mastery and Apprenticeship in the Work of Poets and Lovers," dissertation, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- J. Lewis letters to Elizabeth Madox Roberts, 1922-1932., Photocopies (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Letters to Maurice Leseman from Yvor Winters and Elizabeth Madox Roberts, 1920-1930 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- The Last of the Mohicans; an American Opera. Libretto by Janet Lewis, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Brigitte Hoy Carnochan, The Strength of Art; Poets and Poetry in the lives of Yvor Winters and Janet Lewis: an exhibition of books and manuscripts..., Stanford Univ. Libraries, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Hisaye Yamamoto. Inscription to Lewis in Ayumi; a Japanese American Anthology, 1980, with broadside, "Exile 1942-45" in The rafu shimpo supplement, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Janet Lewis reading at Stanford - Lane Lecture, 5 Nov. 1990., 55 minute video (Box 3, Folder 1)